do we need this like would it would it
make our life no is the answer to that
no no no because this takes J tries to
make it into something that it's not
right like it's like let's take Json and
make it like a structured defined typed
like uh property like it's like that
exists it's called XML oh
[Music]
so we've all been on those pent tests
before right where we're just banging
our head into the external attack
surface of a company for what feels like
an eternity and then when you finally
get inside the network it's like open
freaking season there are accessible
shares everywhere CVS are popping left
and right there's seemingly no controls
at all on what ports can or not be
accessed too many companies are
neglecting their internal network
security and that's why threat Locker
came up with this product Network
control which makes it super easy to
control what kind of ports are Exposed
on a given host whether that be a user
machine or a server the thing I like the
most about Network control is that it
understands far more than just the IP
layer you can allocate specific controls
to keywords or tags and then use those
to manage access from different machines
regardless of whether they change IPS or
not so if you're looking to sh up your
internal Network make sure you check out
Network control by threat Locker all
right let's go back to the
show all righty my man we are rolling on
this beautiful fall day how's it going
oh yeah good how about you pretty good
man the size of the to-do list is is
growing and growing I'm going to um I'm
going to gryl next week for uh gr hacks
and I'm going to be presenting on some
kaido stuff out there and let's just say
that presentation is not fully completed
yet
so that I don't know I don't know some
people I feel like I hear a lot of
hackers talk about how like they'll be
going to this conference and they're
like in their hotel room the night
before prepping the slides and stuff
like that and I've never been that sort
of guy like I'm always the guy that like
has it done way in advance has it
rehearsed that sort of thing but like I
felt like I should try it this time and
I it is not working for me dude no dude
no that's stressful I'm um I mean I'm
over grass to some extent but like for
stuff like that I definitely I wouldn't
want to really be you've got that 8 HD
brain where you can like procrastinate
and then trigger like super power mode
right yeah that doesn't make the
presentation
good I don't know that's drinky part
yeah I suppose so all right all right
what we got on the news for today let's
see um dude this bcrypt thing is insane
okay so let me let me just give a little
bit of a let me just read this um this
release from that OCTA put out okay so
it says for OCTA orgs without MFA sign
on policies and using accounts with
usernames of 52 characters or more this
could allow users to authenticate by
providing only the username and no
password entered or regardless of of the
password entered what the heck dude yeah
so super interesting stuff I somewhere I
guess in the BCP spec it says that it
truncates um inputs Beyond is it 72
characters or 72 bytes uh 52 characters
52 52 characters yeah so um it only
takes you know up to a certain point and
then the rest of it gets truncated
during like hashing I guess um and uh
they were concatenating username and
password together and then hashing that
in bcrypt so if your username was too
long then it would just create a
predictable hash uh that would never get
changed by your password and uh yeah
very very dude I I could you imagine
like this is one of those things like I
want say a couple years back there was
like this scenario with apple where you
could just like press enter a couple
times or something like that and it
would log you in as rout and uh really
yeah oh yeah yeah I forget I forget what
it was called let me see
apple press enter route it was it was
something was a blank pass oh this is in
2017 yeah blank password
yeah yeah click the lock type route in
the username field
and it oh because root had no P oh
that's funny yeah I used to use this
quite a bit actually back back around
that time as well just for like logging
like I had like a secondary user account
yeah and I would use that um so it's
really interesting it's just one of
those things where it's like you would
never expect that to happen to Apple and
you would I personally would never
expect this to happen to OCTA where it's
like there's just no it just doesn't
take a password it's just like one of
those brain [__] things that's like what
is going on here yeah yeah for sure it's
uh it's very very interesting uh bug so
I mean it's good that it got caught how
did they find it or like how did it like
what I didn't see I didn't see the way
that they found it ideally their Buck
Bounty program would have caught
something but um this is just one of
those things that I think it for me
discovered internally oh really
discovered internally wow yeah and their
timeline so July July 23rd it was
introduced uh as part of a standard
release and then on October 30th it was
discovered internally and then they
switched from bcrypt to pbkdf2 yeah and
actually it says down in the comments
here uh that PHP Donette even mentions
that inputs above 72 characters get
truncated so you had 72 in your in your
head but they say 52 in the actual
disclosure um so it's it's one of those
two I well it could be that they have an
additional P so like you know the
speculation I think is that it was
username password but they probably have
like a time stamp or some other thing in
there that's like
right exactly yeah gotcha but either way
very very interesting definitely going
to be on my radar because bcrypt I think
is like something that you see from time
to time when doing white box source code
review so if you see if you see BPT at
all I just GNA have it in my head like
okay there's truncation Happening Here
how might I that truncation and I think
if the username was an email in a lot of
scenarios this becomes a lot a lot
nastier right like I feel like the
length of that could be dram Al longer
and and result in this sort of
truncation yeah for sure it's I mean
it's one of those things where I don't
know how you would find it I guess from
like I I I would be kind of interested
how they found it like what caused them
to find that yeah um I feel like
somebody should have just found it right
like if somebody has a a a super long
username and then they just F their
password loged you in like I would be
like the [__] like what is going on here
I I I think more of it is like you know
from like a security perspective like
you look at that code and you'd be like
okay they're hashing it yeah looks good
they run it through bcrypt they call the
standard bcrypt function okay they
compare it blah whatever right but
unless you know that like bcrypt has
that Quirk or that you've read into the
spec that like bcrypt like I don't think
most security Engineers would second
guess like how bcrypt works bcrypt yeah
right so it's it's very interesting it's
like a very very
bad Edge case yeah that's that's not
great functionality I wonder
Wonder yeah there's not really much I
mean from an attacker's perspective I
think it's not super exploitable because
you know the username has to be so long
so you can only attack victims with
super long usernames or whatever well
and and it depends on like how it's
being done yeah right so like in this
case it's bad because it's username then
password if it was password then
username that'd be completely different
true true but then yeah man they
wouldn't that yeah that's a good point
so really you you have to see that you
have to see that same pattern where
they're concatenating something that is
a part of your in you know a part of the
identifier or like knowable like more
than a password or like you know or
static assault or whatever yeah like an
email like knowing the email not a big
deal knowing the email and password is a
big deal yeah knowing the email and
being able to get in without a password
also a big deal massive deal okay solid
so I mean a little bit of an edge case
there but definitely something to be uh
considering if you're auditing the off
flows of of um these sort of uh
environments where they're they're
dealing with this C uh like password
hashing or using bcrypt I've been I've
been diving a little bit deeper lately
when I've been hacking stuff I've been
trying to look at least
cursorily cursorily c curs c cursorily
Cur I've been looking at least a little
bit at at um at like the implementation
of crypto stuff and and bugs keep on
falling out man I had I had a bug
yesterday where I could bypass the the
signing uh some some signing that was
being passed from the server side into
the client side and uh and then the
validation was being done in ajs library
I bypassed something there and then uh
let's just say at a live hacking event
in the past uh six months there was some
crypto related bugs too so I I think I
was scared of those for a long time um
but I think if you if you understand
some of the basic concepts and then you
look a little bit deeper at the
implementation I think a lot of times
those those sort of issues kind of pop
out
yeah I think you'll find that most of
the time it's not it's not super home
rolled yeah like sometimes sometimes it
is and that can lead to its its own
problems but it's mostly just like in
functionality like how it's being used
or like they're generating this hash and
then they're trusting it and you know
maybe you can poison that Ash or what
you know there's it's more of like the
fundamental principles more than it is
like needing to be a math major to break
sha 2506 or whatever you know the one
the one that I I looked at the other day
was there was a JWT token that was being
passed and uh and it was hardcoding it l
the way that they had written the code
it looked like it was hardcoding the
algorithm that it should be using to
validate it wasn't even using the the
header right um but then if you look a
little bit deeper into the code it it
wasn't it was trusting the algorithm
that was in the the jwbt header so you
could just provide the nun algorithm and
it would still pass um interesting a lot
of libraries have that built in um super
interesting yeah all right let's let's
uh let's jump over to this to this next
one um this is by Nev TK and this is
just a write up of a bunch of Android
specific
Chrome behaviors and compatibilities and
incompatibilities I just thought this
was super fascinating because I think
there's a lot of attack vectors that I
didn't really think about from from an
Android and chrome perspective that he
seems to be really aware of the threat
model with um so I wanted to get your
thoughts on all these Joel what do you
what do you think yeah so I mean I think
a lot of people just sort of jump from
like you know oh you click a link and
then it opens the app or whatever but
that has to happen from somewhere and so
there's a lot of like browser specific
behavior like Android out of the box
ships with chromium as like the Android
web View and then I think it probably
most of them ship with the Chrome app
too most people are probably using the
Chrome app as well um and so there's a
lot of like you know intent URLs I'm
pretty sure that is not like an implicit
feature it's like implemented specific
Ty Ally buy Chrome and chromium into the
browser so that you can launch stuff
with this intense
schema um so there's like a lot of
nuance to how that stuff works the
parameters what's allowed what's not
allowed what stuff you can launch like
how it get the pars all that kind of
stuff so this is a a really good
in-depth like look at that kind of stuff
as well as it seems there was a number
of issues with like just the format of
it how how it was being parsed and all
that kind of stuff as well like separate
from how it's supposed to work um so
very very interesting stuff they got
quite a number of bounties I I like he
how how they mentioned some of the
attack vectors that I wouldn't really
have known about without going through
and and reading like the chromium issues
for example apparently it's a problem
that uh can be awarded $3,000 because
that's what happened here um if you can
force another browser to pop up uh from
chrome without a prompt apparently
there's supposed to be some sort of
prompt saying hey we're going to open
this URL in Samsung browser and the
reason for that is because like if you
if like Samsung browser is running on a
on a much older version of of chromium
as a base right so if you can pivot from
chrome and force it to open up Samsung
browser then that makes it you know your
chain there becomes a lot easier to do
some something like a like a browser um
end day attack on that older version is
that accurate is that what you saw as
well well I mean like that that's true
generally speaking you don't want to
make it so that can open other apps or
like spawn intents from one app to
another app and especially not without
that confirmation dialogue so there's
this like this this concept of
registered schemes right and so if let's
say you have two browsers on your device
and they both register the HTTP scheme
and you open a link it should prompt you
and say do you want to open this in
Chrome do you want to open this in Opera
do you want to open this in whatever and
if it doesn't implicitly by like
directly opening a specific App instead
of prompting the user to do it then
that's you know obviously a
vulnerability just like manifesting
itself within the browser application
right so um yeah it's it's it's awesome
research and uh definitely a lot of good
Snippets in here just generally speaking
about like the intent URL uh schema like
format and like how that stuff works and
what stuff you can do with it what like
the parameters are all that kind of
stuff so um this is yeah we talked about
that a little bit I think on the mobile
episode where we were talking about
intent URLs and how all that works but I
think that is something that like if you
want to level up as a mobile hacker like
I think one of the next things on my as
a mobile hacker would be I need to
understand how all of those work so that
I can make my expat more reliably um
like I guess what would it be
Network ra theity of them because you
know even if it may be a more complex
attack you might be able to launch it
from the browser instead of like having
to rely on another app on the device
right then it goes from like adjacent to
to like remotely exploitable right if
they click a link in their browser
so it still requires user interaction
but it's still it it allows you to
access some of those like more intent
some core some more core Android um
exploitation techniques if you
understand how those work that's pretty
rad yeah and I feel like there's there's
a lot of crap that ships with uh with
Android devices and with like Samsung
devices and stuff like that like a lot
of apps and so um I think there's
probably a lot of more ripe attack
surface than I I actually gave it credit
for actually attacking like vanilla
Android devices and say like all right
let's grab all of these these apps that
come pre-installed and develop exploits
that do things like for example opening
up specific apps without a prompt well
and you'll see that like you know nine
times out of 10 when there is a
vulnerability in like Samsung or
something that's like not a kernel
exploit it is that it's like there's a
permissions issue in one of the system
apps that's installed at a system level
that has additional privileges and you
can escalate through that by doing
something in Secure through just like a
standard Android
mechanism very cool yeah I'm looking
through some of these other ones man and
and there's like um add to home screen
spoof there's like um an iframe escape
and some of these haven't been uh fixed
yet it says asked and not fixed
controlling Google Assistant asked and
not fixed the the controlling Google
Assistant one is actually kind of scary
to me man because it looks like you can
um you know trigger the user to go to a
a deep link or whatever and it will
invoke specific routines or workflows in
inside of Google Assistant which yeah I
would not want that to happen right like
I have
some man my offs SEC is so bad dude but
I have I have some some routine set up
at my house that will that will do
things with my home automation right and
I'm like I don't want people invoking
that remotely so I'm I'm kind of
confused about why this Google app col
deeplink and then passing in this whole
URL I'm kind of confused as to why that
wasn't fixed by by Google yeah yeah it's
very interesting I mean it might be that
it's part of I me you never know like
I'm Google is not the kind of team that
I generally am like worried that they're
mishandling vulnerabilities so usually
if they have like taken a stance on
something it's very
very specific for a valid reason and
like either they're working on fixing it
or there's a threat model like or
there's mitigating factors or whatever
I'm sure that there some reason um you
know I I don't think I've ever really
seen an instance where the Google
security team has like Mis valued
something or like not paid something
properly well there was that YouTube
thing a little while ago but but I it's
pretty I don't know if that was like I
don't know if that was necessarily like
Mis payment per se but they could have
maybe paid higher yeah I mean and to be
honest I often see like we talked about
on the podcast I think a couple weeks
ago or maybe I was just tweeting about
it I forget but there's there was a um a
vulnerability that was essentially a
clickjacking that that worked out and
and got paid or an iframe injection
that's what it was it was like an and
then it got paid uh 15 grand was that
yeah I I want to don't know I don't no
no no no no it's a different one this is
for Google so it was it was a um it was
a uh iframe injection so you were able
to control what ined into an frame and
then somehow used it to get account
takeover apparently but 15 you Clarity
on yeah I I think the the result of that
was very similar to like the the person
wasn't very explicit about it I
commented on that and and they responded
and said um the result of that was
something similar to that that Google
Drive one we saw a while back where it's
like you could embed like there was like
side chains yeah it was kind of similar
to that where you could you know Force
share some Google drive or like your
root Google Drive um folder but I think
he was able to get his to account
takeover so 15 grand make sense for that
I guess yeah I mean I think if you can
figure out how to open arbitrary URLs
within a Google product that's usually
like a really good foothold yeah um and
probably one of the more common
footholds you're GNA like see like you
know because they have fairly strict
like CSP and like like CSP valuat is
written by Google so yeah yeah um so I'm
looking I'm looking through this whole
thing we'll link it down below I would
actually recomend any any of the
listeners that are trying to understand
a little bit more about um I guess
intermediate to Advanced uh like mobile
attack vectors I think this write up is
really good not only because it it talks
about some of these more Fringe Fringe
features like the intent URLs and that
sort of thing but um also because it it
talks about understanding the threat
models of um these various apps and
ecosystems right you know I I did not
know that if you could bypass that
little that little popup that says like
all right we're going to open Samsung
browser now you know press approve that
that was going to result in a in a
bounty um so understanding those threat
models is one of the ways you can really
stay on top of finding uh vules in these
sort of more complex environments yeah
for sure and and I I think what I'd say
is like to that specific instance just
think about it like as if it's any other
app right if you can open another app
from PayPal that's an issue if you can
open another app from chrome that's also
an issue like without user user
authorization right really I I didn't
know that so that that little box that
pops up from the bottom is that is that
what you're talking about where it's
like open with that so if you can bypass
that that's a problem yes okay well
today I learned cool well we'll link
this Nev TK um uh right up in the in the
description so check that out um if
you're want some more details on that um
dude another another ports wiger
research drop you see me I'm rubbing the
hands together guys I'm excited I wonder
know how much they're paying these guys
dude they've been they they crank out
some serious stuff man they really do
James Kettle just hit like 10 years
right at ports sger he's like I love it
here like dang bro it's a good I always
hear these Europeans or wait UK is not
part of Europe I always hear these
people over the
seas on the other side of the Atlantic
Ocean exactly um talking about how they
get they don't get these Bay Area
engineering salaries but uh somehow they
managed to capture James Kettle and
Gareth Hayes for I so many years I feel
like you gota yeah you got to just write
a a blank check to Gareth hay and and
Kettle man like those guys maybe that's
why they raised money yeah maybe they
raised they raised funding so they could
pay their salaries yeah seriously um
this one this one was really cool though
it's titled concealing payloads in url
credentials and I've got a couple
comments on this one it's you guys know
me you guys know me and my client love
of client side stuff so I see this and I
just I just want to like give Gareth a
hug because this stuff is so nice um but
actually it it originated from Johan
Carlson uh talking about how you this
sort of similar functionality um on
Twitter a while back um and it's not
visible in the URL the function was in
Twitter or he was talking about it on
Twitter no no he was talking about it on
Twitter and essentially what this is is
it's using the um the username and
password parts of the URL right so
you've got
HTTP HTP
and
then passw yeah exactly so that and um
you know you can navigate to those URLs
in Chrome and it just won't show
anything in the URL in the URL bar but
and it won't show anything in window
location.href but it will show something
in document. url so this is um this is
another way that you can smuggle payload
information into a page without like
affecting the actual URL of the page or
putting anything in hash or giving the W
anything to work with because it's it's
client side um so it was it was
surprising to to both Gareth and to me
that location and document. URL are
different um and that you know
definitely provides some some ability to
um to play around with this and he he
pointed out really well that if that URL
is actually being embedded into a an a
tag or something like that and that a
tag has a a an ID associated with it
then you can very easily access that
value by using you know ID with like Dom
clobbering like functionality by using
ID in this case it was X do username or
do password and that will return that
string that you smuggled in um yeah so I
have a suspicion as to why this is the
case and if you look if you look kind of
closely at it um document. URL is a
string right so uh either it's crafted
or it's set or whatever you know
somewhere do location and window.
location is a location object right so
it's parsed so cuz I was curious if
there was like a user name property on
the location object or something but it
doesn't appear there is but you'll
notice that it is it's a it's a it's an
object it's a location object it's not
um it's not like docu and document. URL
is literally just a string yeah so I'm
wondering there might be other instances
where that like exists as a proxy or
something yeah you know like I said like
maybe there's another object object that
has a URL property on it or something
that's that's nested somewhere else so
window location. is also a string but
that H is well that's going to come from
the location object right yeah yeah it
it does and it doesn't contain that
username username and password there
either um yeah so my guess is that the
location object Constructor probably
like parses it out specifically and then
when you dohre it basically like goes
back it it like parses it and then turns
it back into a string yeah yeah no
absolutely and I think I think that um
oh just as a note I'm just going to
mention this before I forget Safari does
discard the URL so this only works in
Chrome and Firefox which is crazy
normally you see the other way around
where Chrome does something and Safari
is like H let me do saari is the new
security champ yeah so I I did want to
mention a couple other things you know
because we talked about last week how
Safari has some weird cookie attribute
commenting out functionality um but uh
the this whole concept of smuggling data
through
um
and in such a way that the wff cannot
see it I think is really valuable and um
you know there's a lot of really unique
um payloads out there for xss but my my
favorite one which is in line with this
is simply JavaScript colon name okay
that is a a full xss payload and the
reason for that is that you you can
assign the name value that that name
attribute window. name persists
acrossing it's not clobbering it
actually persists across window
refreshes right so I open a window and I
name it whatever I want I can name it
SVG onload alert one right and then when
I redirect to that JavaScript URL
JavaScript colon name what it does is it
returns from that JavaScript URL the
name String right and then that name the
value of the name String gets considered
to be the Dom of that page under the
same origin that it came from so if I
put SVG onload alert one into the name
and then redirect to that via JavaScript
colon name it will actually render the
SVG tag on the page in pop alert and
there's no way that the W can see that
name is actually always always exists
it's a it always exists there's also I
mean there's a lot of things that
actually follow fall so window.
persistent all caps is a one it just
holds the value one
so so if you did like JavaScript call
and alls
persistent that would or alert
persistent no no no I mean yeah you
could you could do there's lots of
variables that are accessible you know
at that at that capacity but can you
just do like javascripts colon one does
that work uh well that yeah that'll put
one on the page isn't that weird like
like that that was what freaked me out
one time is I like did something that
returned one or whatever and then I saw
it appear on on the page and I'm like
what is going on here and it's well
documented I I thought for a second that
I had found something weird here but if
you look at it you know JavaScript colon
name is a pretty popular payload you
know it's well documented but it's just
crazy to me that you can you don't have
to do any assignment you don't have to
do anything like that right if you
control the location that it's being
directed to you can just do JavaScript
colon name and you don't have to do any
function calls anything like that
because a lot of times the W block they
block the the back text and they block
the parentheses right so it makes it
really hard to actually call functions
in this scenario you can smuggle
everything through window. name which is
something the Waf never even sees yeah
and interestingly because name is an
empty string by default you could
concatenate to it with plus as well so
if you did like name plus one you would
get one in a string yeah so you could
potentially pivot off of um off of that
as well yeah there's there's lots of
lots of cool quirks there and then so
bringing this back around to the
research that they were talking about
with with um with the URL stuff this is
another way to smuggle in data that the
that the um the W never even sees right
so you can smuggle in by a name you can
smuggle it in Via hash or you can
smuggle it in Via um you know this
username and password functionality uh
and if that username and password gets
embedded into an a tag then you have a
really easy way to access that with
whatever ID do username or do password
so yeah pretty pretty cool stuff super
interesting
all right now we got the monster man you
ready you ready for this guy I don't
know if I'm ready for this guy this this
is a pretty intense one PHP strikes
again dude we got to talk about it
though so there's this this tool that
got released this past week called lie
and this is um one of those things
that like I feel like I should probably
read through this and understand it
fully but when I when I read through it
and I try to this is one of those things
that I'm going to put a pin in it until
I need it next time see a PHP page I'm
going to be like a God damn it here we
go dude that's a good that's a good
thank you that's what I'm doing too that
that makes me feel a little bit better
about this right but um the tldr of this
and I wanted to to give it some
publicity because I mean this is a [__]
ton of work and a [__] ton of of um you
know uh code that they had to write in
in intricacies that they had to
understand to get get us this tool this
tool allows you to abuse those PHP
filter change that we talked about on
the Pod a while back and um there's a
the current state-of-the-art tool for
that is or prior to this one was PHP
filter chains Oracle exploit and um they
outlined in the beginning of this that
there's a pretty big downside to this
which is that um if you're primitive is
via a get parameter right so if you're
injecting into a an open or or whatever
where you can use the um the the F the
the um PHP schemes um then if you're
doing this via get parameter then your
the size of that get parameter inflates
pretty quickly if you're trying to to to
get data out so you can only get about
135 characters out before you start
hitting the URI to Long problem right um
and this tool light year not only fixes
that it it can dumb files of tens of
thousands of bytes a with just small
payloads of a couple thousand characters
um but it also does it a lot faster um
and and does it more efficiently and
doesn't produce any PHP warnings or
errors which will sometimes break the
whole the whole flow so I I think you
don't want that pesky IR team knowing
what we're doing I know exactly right so
this is a this is an awesome tool if
you're if you're able to actually inject
into any of those sort of um uh
functions that that allow you to utilize
those PHP schemes um it's a for me I
don't do a lot of PHP hacking so uh this
is I think I'm gonna do exactly what you
said Joel that that that makes so much
sense to me it's just when next time I'm
hacking PHP next time I need this I know
exactly where to find this bookmark um
but it's nice to know that that they've
got something that really allows you to
read arbitrary files with with that I
think that's a really important part of
learning is like knowing when you should
really learn something and when you
should have it ready to be learned you
know because there's only there's a
certain point uh when I was young and
Invincible I had infinite brain space I
am now old and no longer invincible and
have limited brain space and so I have
to I have to really pick and choose what
I decide to keep yeah yeah and well I
mean I think that's absolutely necessary
in this environment as well in the in
the it environment right the
particularly the security environment
where there's so much like onslaught of
amazing research and stuff you know
we're in this very small niche of bug
Bounty and I can't even keep up right
like and it's my job to keep up you know
um and so I think having these sort of
categorized um and knowing where to find
them when you need them is important so
light years's the new go-to tool for
that it seems like they've a lot of the
problems we can use small payloads we
can do it really fast there's no errors
or or Warnings so um that's a good one
to have in the in your back pocket for
sure but Joel did you see the little
thing I added underneath this in the
docks oh I didn't actually that was the
one link I didn't click no dude so it's
like oh there's
a wait but this is old no so they're I
think they're going to implement it now
though so I see they referenced this
issue four days ago yeah so back in 2023
when this whole um PHP filter chains uh
research came out someone was like Hey
we got to fix this in PHP and um and
they're like nah and then when when this
this uh this new research came out
they're like all right we got to fix
this so I think at some point they're
going to limit the number of um filters
that you can apply which I think would
kill a lot of This research so yeah this
guy uh some some guy mentioned this I
didn't know you could do this this is
one of those annoying things about
GitHub that you can like there's always
like ways to like make yourself appear
on things yeah and so I guess he
mentioned this issue on his own repo in
a commit and it like like populated but
some guy has added like a limit to the
number of filters into the PHP into a
fork of the PHP Source uh so if see if
it actually gets pulled in or not but if
you want to do that yourself you can I
guess yeah oh it's a PR I'm stupid yeah
it's a PR so I think I think it I think
it should be I think there yeah so
somebody open a PR chaining filter
becoming increasingly popular primitive
to exploit PHP applications blah blah
blah blah yeah so we'll see I mean it
still has to be AC accepted I haven't
it's just going to be a configurable
option right like there's plenty of
dangerous things that are in PHP that
you have to enable as a configuration
option yeah even though that's a lot of
people do turn these things on it's just
going to be you know somebody's going to
be like oh number of filters negative
one or whatever like and and then you'll
have the same problem but for now yeah
at least it'll be like you know secure
by default which is good yeah absolutely
man alrighty Richard what's on the
docket for today oh an ASMR ad say L I
got you I got you all right guys so
today we're gonna ah attack surface
management roles not as okay I got you
well for talking about a tax surfice
management then of course we're talking
about the assd note team right the ogs
in the ASM space and this time around
they've released a new community project
their attack surface management job
board a place where you can see all of
the companies that are hiring for attack
surface management jobs so if you're
interested in that sort of thing if
you're a Recon heavy hacker or if you
just want to get your hands on the as&
no product to play around with it um
then definitely check out that jobboard
that's going to be at aset
note. aset note. ASMR I'm going to make
him change it to ASMR so if you want to
support the Pod or if you want to check
out that job board head over to asset
note. ASMR all right back to the show
let's go okay so um moving on to this
this next one um there's a release from
yes we hack on a a tool called Dom
Explorer and uh its architect of course
is our boy bit k um and I just got to
say man I think I've been sleeping on
yes we hack a little bit like I think
yes we hack is actually put putting out
some really solid stuff a lot of which
is coming from bit cat it's sh I'm not
woring about yes we ha cat right now I
know dude I we got to go get our swag
cuz the swag they sent out was really
really high quality too um but they
seems like they're actually dumping a
lot of really cool um toys for for
hackers right because we mentioned
before they've got that exploit or that
xss exploitation framework right that
makes it really easy to exploit um xss
and xville information and it's got a
bunch of um sort of modulized
exploitation vectors um okay I'm sorry
hold on Joel I I have something
modulized no no something like that but
I I'm actually gonna just totally
deviate from this really quickly because
I I I I wanted to mention something that
I did the other day that I thought was
really cool okay
okay so on the on the concept of of xss
exploitation I was in this scenario all
right come Story Time with Justin let's
go okay I I was I was in a scenario
right where I had a um a page that was
triggering a redirect and
then and then writing my my data to the
Dom right via in HTML so it shouldn't
trigger right because the redirect will
would delete the Dom you know before it
actually writes to the Dom and it's one
of those things where you're like you're
redirecting but then if it's too slow
we'll let you click this button right
that that does like a a redirect right
and I had the injection into this button
um okay and so here's what I did I just
wanted to put this on on y''s
I I the host that I I'm I was
redirecting to that the page was
redirecting to was controllable by me uh
to a certain degree but it had to be
whitelisted right so what I did is the
domains were Whit listed but the port
was not wh listed so so what I did is I
get got a valid domain and I I put you
know semicolon 1337 so now it's
redirecting to a page that uh doesn't
have an open port on it right so it's
trying to is set up that TCP connection
and it's retrying and it's retrying and
it's waiting and it doesn't remove the
Dom of that page until it opens that
that TCP connection with the next page
the navigation doesn't actually occur
right so that allowed the delay to be
long enough for it to write my my
payload to the Dom all right but that's
not the end of it Joel listen to this
okay so now I I've got my payload
written written to the Dom but there's a
wff there's a wff dude and so what do I
do I'm like okay of course I just use
like location name you know just like
talked about earlier you send like
880,000 A's yeah
there's well that that that could work
too but
um classic move um but the the the W was
really getting in the way and it was and
it was blocking any function call and I
can't use location because there's
already a location change in progress
right so it wouldn't let me override
that so here's what I did dude I didn't
actually get the full exploit to work um
what I did was is I set window. name
equal to document.cookie
right so now I've I've set name equal to
cookie and name persist refreshes right
so then from my attacker control tab
because I opened this this tab where the
exploit is happening I can control where
that tab goes so then I redirect it back
to an attacker controlled origin I reach
into that Dom and read the name property
and I can leak the cookies on that page
um us it as like a a holder yeah yeah so
it's like it's like a way to steal
information out of those sort of
environments uh without actually
executing any functions CU it's just
name equals document.cookie or whatever
I'll see you in three months when Chrome
patches that D isolate the name variable
it's a pretty it's a pretty it's a
pretty Niche scenario um but I just
thought I'd mention it as well because I
think there are a lot of scenarios where
where wafts are kind of a pain in the
ass to bypass when when you're dealing
with um you know execu you're actually
getting JS execution but you can't
trigger function calls um and so having
some way to smuggle data back out via
the window. name I think could be a
pretty useful technique for people um
yeah for sure so okay so the the reason
I went on that was that xss tools thing
um which was triggered by Dom Explorer
so now now we're got to talk about Dom
Explorer are you still with me Joel I'm
still um Dom
Explorer inspired by cyberchef but looks
nothing like it
oh my gosh dude I'm sorry I I I had to
rant there for a
second all right so Dom Explorer I guess
this one's mine too because I'm the I'm
the the D the Dom geek you want me to
want me to talk about this one I mean it
it's so basically I I feel like uh I I I
saw like a screenshot of something that
was very similar to this maybe it was
during the dawn purify by uh xss like a
couple months ago yeah I Carlson has
something doesn't he yeah yeah somebody
I think somebody had scrapped together
something very simple where you
basically just put an input in and then
it would like you click a button and it
just runs it through Dom purifying CD
output yeah so that's basically what
this is right where you have um this Dom
Explorer tool and you can create a pip
line of you know that that's where it's
very much so like cyberchef where you
have like steps that you can run an
input through and so you can say Okay I
want to run it through Dom purify I want
to run it through this parser or
whatever the sanitizer Etc
and you can have this pipeline of of
steps that your your input goes through
and then you can inspect what the output
would be after all of those different
pipeline steps um and so that can be
really really helpful when you're you
know trying to exploit an XS in some
specific environment you know it's going
through X Y and Z sanitizer and renderer
and parser and whatever and you just
want to really quickly rapidly test
inputs see what stuff you can get
through instead of sending request wait
3 seconds request wait 3 seconds you can
build out that Pipeline on the Dom
Explorer and test your inputs and then
when you're pretty sure you you know
have a bypass you can actually go test
it yeah and I think this is helpful for
looking at those sort of scenarios where
you've got a stack a on a on a open
source software that you want to pone
and it's like okay it's using like Dom
purify and then it's putting it into
this and then or maybe it's putting into
this like HTML renderer on the on the
server side and then you know uh it's
exporting as a PDF or something like
that and you can chain together these
pieces and see how they how they um
interact together um and yeah I did find
that that thing you mentioned dude it's
um it's of Leen Brun it's Matias Carlson
it's a a tool called multi HTML parse
and I'll add this to the to the docs as
well so it gets put in the um in the
notes um but I think as many of these as
we can get the better because there's so
many different Frameworks for parsing
HTML and and rendering stuff um so I I
think that's really good the one thing I
like about um Dom Explorer which is the
the one by S hack that we're talking
about right now is that um it's actually
in the browser so uh and it's set up and
you don't have to do like Docker or
anything it's just like go to yes Weck
doget up.i d-explorer
and it will give you this interface
where you can play with it um and you
can add a ton of different parsers so
Dom parser parse 5 Dom purify JS xss all
sorts of stuff um and so you know if if
maybe if it isn't in uh uh this one this
tool Dom Explorer then you know might be
in multi HTML pars or vice versa and I
think as we sort of build these tools up
it becomes a lot easier to find mutation
xss right where where different parsers
are treating things differently and um
and Trigger those more Universal xss
scenarios where you're you're bypassing
some white lists that are are like
absolutely pivotal to security yeah yeah
absolutely um and there's like lots of
configuration options as well on the uh
on Dom Explorer so like for example like
Dom parser um it has you know what's the
MIM type that you're feeding into it DOC
does it have a doc type what selector
are you feeding it what's the output for
like and so you can you know you can
really get sort of pretty narrow down on
it and you can um make it very very
accurate to what you're testing against
so that it works very very well and it's
good for testing yeah very solid dude
yeah yeah so definitely to keep an eye
on the the yes we hack GitHub stuff
because they especially you know what
bit K's been releasing lately has really
been kind of putting them on the map for
me I
think yeah absolutely super super cool
tool this is another one of the ones
like everything else I bookmark it put
in my yeah my tools list and then I
don't think about I don't think about it
until I need it
um all right what we got next here this
last one yeah yeah let me see yeah Jason
done okay I I had a bone to pick with
this okay all right well okay so I put
this in here because I'm like you know I
feel like Json is something that we deal
with a lot right
we're the listeners don't have context
to the doc let me I put a link in here
that that essentially allows you to
visualize Json a little bit easier and
and the thought was this
um is there a place for Json
visualization
progress in our our HTTP proxy tools
because 90% of the time we're dealing
with Json right the request bodies are
are request Json and I feel like you
know we spend a decent amount of time
modifying attributes and like moving
things around and that sort of thing and
I wonder if it would be better to have
some sort of visualizer inside of the
HTP proxies that makes it easier to to
to work with Json what do you what do
you think about that I think the only
thing I would like to see is JQ
searching that's it what is JQ searching
oh JQ like search searching J JQ format
searching so so like being able to
filter by attributes using a JQ Cy and
just like put that in a search box I
know you can do it in um paw uh now
rapid API um but like the the Paw like
API tool it's kind of like Postman
insomnia you know whatever you choose to
use but yeah um it has a a thing in like
the response format where you can filter
down um you know whatever your your
response
like ay like that so you could do you
know like dot attribute or whatever and
you'll only see that in your output so I
think that would be really nice um you
know this is it's an interesting tool
right so so this Json crack thing it's
like um a Json editor it's like
visualizes Json graphs but yeah and and
I feel like Jon wasn't this wasn't
necessarily the thing that I was trying
to like talk about like Json we can talk
about Json crack but the the concept
more that I was thinking of is like do
we need this like would it would it make
our life no is the answer to that no no
no because this takes Jon and tries to
make it into something that it's not
right like it's like let's take Json and
make it like a structured defined type
like uh property like it's like that
exists it's called XML oh jeez yeah no
and we don't want to go closer to XML
for sure yeah yeah you know okay maybe
maybe I'm off base with that I just I
just think you know that said though
it's worth challening
we that we need to modify in the request
body and actually I've got a solution
for that that I'm going to be releasing
in in a couple weeks it's not
specifically for that but it it can do
this as well um so we'll uh we'll see
when I'll talk about that when that
episode goes live and we'll see if we
still need to address these sort of um
the sort of way that we interact with um
the these various content types I I do
want to say as
well and I told this to the kaido team
and and I think this is something that
is on the in the pipeline but I feel
like both burp and kaido
should automatically just change the
content type based off of what format
you have in the request body does that
not make sense like um like I mean sure
it should be a checkbox you know where
it's like okay you know do you want us
to automatically update the content type
like we update the content length but
like it's very easy to determine whether
the request body is Json XX form URL
encoded or multiart yeah I I will say
like one of my one of the more annoying
things in recent burp updates recent I
don't know within the last like two
years is the Json like Auto formatting
that thing drives me crazy when I'm
typing in the request and like I'll put
like a quote and then it like adds a new
line because it's trying to format it
and then I put another quote and then it
like brings it back because it's closed
the string it's hard Json Jon formatting
I think is a really challenging piece so
that's that's why I'm kind of wondering
is like is there a better way to
approach this um yeah I don't know I
think the visual the visual editor could
be like a nice touch I just think it
kind of over complicates things and then
like I want to say there was an
interphase in burp at one point where
they were like where you could switch
the way that the request bodies were
represented and then it would give you
like a text box on the left hand side
and a text box on the right hand side
and like did did you ever see that or am
I hallucinating that's how I use my burp
is that not how you use burp what that's
how mine looks is that on what your burp
looks like wait no no no when you're man
when you're manually modifying the the
request body yeah you don't have
to maybe maybe I maybe I just need to to
be fair I I haven't opened burp in a
long time but uh yeah I I think that's
nice for for I think that that is nice
for for um for X form Ur all encoded but
I don't I don't you know I feel like
something like that for Json could be
really helpful as well I don't know just
a thought yeah I know hack hack verter
does that too with like previews oh so
like you can do like a hack verter
preview in the like replay Tab and stuff
and it has like a left like a input
output thing and all
that that that's pretty rad I think that
would be good dude okay on let me see if
I got permission to talk about the thing
that I was going to to talk
about yes I did okay they messaged me
back in time sweet all right so let me
just tack this on at the end here of the
podcast um and I'll probably talk about
it a different podcast as well but um
you know a while ago you and I talked
about on the Pod about building somebody
needs to build a freaking notes plugin
for kaido and for burp that is good
right that that has markdown rendering
that I found the guy man that guy is
static flow Tanner and um and it's good
man I I've I've seen it he's he's been
kind of working that's the guy I know oh
yeah yeah dude he built he built out
this tool and it and it rocks uh I've
been playing with it and it's really
well structured um the the markdown
rendering is really clean it supports
exports we're working on like a sync
feature where it'll sync to a specific
part of the file system um I'm going to
use it man that's where I'm going to
write all my reports and all of my um
you know notes and uh I think I think
that'll be the go-to methodology because
then you don't have to jump in and out
of your your proxy you can just say and
and he has it um tied to a key binding
as well so I'm like in my report I click
you know whatever the key binding is we
just implemented that feature so I
haven't played with that yet but jump
into the key binding and then you're in
your notes and you're type type type and
then I like that how do like that uh and
then the type type type um uh so I'm
excited for this um I I I'll link it in
the description depending on when this
episode airs I'm not sure if it'll
actually be live yet or not but um yeah
I think it will be um so definitely
check that out I think it'll be really
uh so the the kaido one will be released
by the time this episode come out I
don't know that the burp one will but I
know that he is working on a burp
version of this as well and I think this
is going to take over the notes market
for the for the plugins yeah yeah for
sure yeah because it's just kind of like
you know it's like your Evernote or your
obsidian right but it's just built in to
kind oh here's the other feature dude
that's crazy you can link replay tabs
in it so you can say like hey you know
this specific replay tab has yeah he
showed me when he did when he did that
he was like yeah check this out and you
it's like links it and you just click it
just like opens the
tab dude it's so good I why haven't we
had that I don't I don't know but H
because burp is uh swing based yeah well
that's what he said he's like it's so
much harder to code this in burp
because it's a pain in the ass but yeah
kaido I think because it's it's just you
know JavaScript and HTML there's a lot
of libraries you know you can use for
that so makes it much easier to D there
yeah for sure all right man cool is that
a wrap is that the Pod I think that's it
all right peace
peace and that's a wrap on this episode
of critical thinking thanks so much for
listening and if you want more critical
thinking content head over to ctbb show/
Discord join the Discord there's lots of
great conversations and chats going on
over there and if you want to support
the show there's the Discord subscriber
tiers which give you access to Master
Class amas hack alongs exclusive scripts
and an exclusive chat Channel with us
we'll see you there